翻译:幽蓝星晴/Geoff鲲/jimny99/石佛/natas/aiolia
校对:顿顿/jimny99/清野过客
后期特效/压制:最沉重的负担/清野过客
视频资料来自网络 版权归BBC所有
仅供学习交流使用 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
R.I.P 尼尔森·曼德拉 R.I.P 保罗·沃克
新浪微博关注topgear吧字幕组
大英帝国的星期二
It's a normal Tuesday in Britain.
山雨欲来风满楼 漫漫车龙几时休
There's a hint of drizzle in the air and traffic is at a standstill.
我们认为 驾驶不该如此乏味
We know that driving is meant to be more fun than this.
车也不该如此无聊
We know that cars are meant to be more fun than this.
所以我们决定 帮你逃离这一切
So we decided what we'd do is give you an hour or so of escapism,
给你一个小时亲近好车 亲近完美之路
of perfect roads and perfect cars.
我们接下来
Yeah. So, what we're going to do is
要将所有会产生烦恼的东西抹去
strip away all the things that drive us mad,
道路施工 小标致 测速探头
roadworks, Peugeots, speed cameras...
-詹姆斯·梅 -对 我们不能带上他
- James May.
- Yeah, we'll get rid of him.
他会拖我们后腿
He's always holding us up.
然后开始我们的完美公路之旅
And then we will end up with the perfect road trip.
奇怪的是 杰里米坚持要从威尼斯
Strangely, Jeremy insisted we should start here, in Venice,
这个没有街道只有水道的地方出发
where all the streets are full of water.
我们为什么要来威尼斯
Why are we in Venice?
因为我想驾驶这台Riva Aquarama号
Because I wanted to drive the Riva Aquarama.
为什么
Why?
因为它是有史以来最曼妙的小艇
Because it's the most beautiful thing ever made
而且还拥有一对V8发动机
and because it's got two V8s.
很好 我们来威尼斯 是因为他想开 啥来着
Okay, we are starting in Venice because he wanted to drive a... What is it?
- Riva Aquarama号
- Riva Aquarama.
这世界上最美的东西
- The most beautiful thing ever made
而且有 两台V8
and it's got... Two V8s?
两台
- Two V8s!
我们将由此出发 穿越
And we're going to set off from here on a journey across Italy,
意大利 法国 直抵 哪里
across France, to... Where are we going?
-波城 -波城 是哪里
- Pau. - To Pau... Pau?
为什么要去波城
Why are we going to Pau?
因为那是第一届格兰披治大赛的举办地
Because that is where the first ever Grand Prix was held.
-波城 -没错
- Pau? - Yeah.
-闻所未闻 -当年的赛道还在呢
- Never heard of it. - The track's still there.
我们将在史上首条格兰披治赛道上飞驰
We're going to drive the very first Grand Prix track.
话说回来 在起点和终点间 我们将途径
Whatever. Between here and there, we're going to be on motorways,
高速 山路 拉力赛道 场地赛道和城市
mountain roads, rally stages, racetracks and cities.
在每个点 我们都会使用
And in every place, we are both going to pick what we believe
自认为最棒的交通工具
is the perfect mode of transport.
这将会是美好的一周
It's going to be the perfect week.
蓝天白云 游艇美景 万事俱备
Perfect weather, perfect start,
perfect boat, perfect everything!
-爽 -而且詹姆斯不在
- Perfect.
- And no James May.
不能要求 再多
That's better than perfect.
接下来的七天 我们的完美之旅
Over the next seven days, our quest for perfection
将带我们从威尼斯前往意大利湖区
would take us from Venice towards the Italian Lakes.
然后从那里往南 奔赴地中海
From there we'd head south to the Mediterranean,
沿着法国里维埃拉沿岸 到达圣特罗佩
for a drive along the French Riviera to Saint-Tropez.
并再次向内陆进发 到达终点波城
Then we'd swing inland again towards the finishing point at Pau.
我们是不是看上去有点像美帝警探
Do we look like Tubbs and Crockett?
或者天朝城管
Or Tubby and Crotchety?
-不 说真的 太爽了 -天朝城管
- No, seriously. That's perfect, though.
- Tubby and Crotchety.
大威尼斯
Venice Vice.
靠泊好20万英镑的快艇后
Having docked the £200,000 speedboat,
我选择了一台价格更贵的跑车
I switched to an even more expensive car.
全新成熟版 不甩尾版 黑版 SLS
The new, grown-up, less tail-happy Black edition of the SLS.
维多利亚时期 人们会在周游列国时
In Victorian times, people would come through Venice
路过威尼斯
on what was called "the grand tour",
我为此钦点奔驰到场
so that's why I've gone for the Mercedes,
因为它是绝对的终极自驾游神器
because it is the ultimate grand tourer.
它当然不是 因为你忘记了法拉利F12
Mmm-hmm. Except, it isn't the ultimate because this is, the Ferrari F12.
不对 那车动力太强了
No, no. That's too powerful.
-动力太强 -是啊
- Too powerful?
- It is too powerful.
我之前就说过
I said that... It is!
你是节目里说过 然后我就呵呵了
You did say it on the programme and I thought then...
你看 我有能力驾驭它的全部动力
You see this? I will be able to use all of the power.
然后
Yes?
而你根本没办法榨干那台F12
In that, you will not be able to use all of the power
不然你会在半途撞上电线杆
because you'll end up halfway up a telegraph pole.
不 我绝对可以尽在掌握
No, I'll be able to all of the power
肯定还会剩余那么一点点 就是这样
but there will be more power than you've got, that's all that's about.
一台GT必须
A grand tourer should be powerful
够快 够强 够狠
- and creamy and grunty and... - Uh...
一台622匹马力的四轮车
Six hundred and twenty-two horsepower,
it's not a wheelbarrow.
-730匹 比你还多 -我知道
- Seven hundred and thirty! It's more.
- I know.
哈蒙德
Hammond!
我们能开着GT上路了么
Let's just go across Italy, shall we, in our grand tourers?
走 走
Yes. Yes.
我会狂飙的 小样
I'LL go quickly, you big girl.
欧 我的天
Oh, God!
动力太凶猛了
Oh, that's a lot of power!
确实多了点 不 一点也不
Maybe that's too much! No, it's not too much.
杰里米个胆小鬼 动力正合适
Jeremy's being a wuss. It's just enough.
只是我目前用不了这么多
It's just I don't need to use all of it right now.
我要控制一些 就这么一点
I'm going to use a bit Less. Maybe this much of it.
变速箱的换挡速度太惊人了
The changes from that gearbox are incredible.
这是台双离合变速箱 其实
It's a double clutch gear box. In actual fact,
它和杰里米SLS里的那台一模一样
it's exactly the same unit as in Jeremy's Mercedes SLS.
但法拉利进行了独门调教
It's just Ferrari have put their own mapping,
用法拉利的电脑控制它
their own computer control on this particular one.
能在你换挡的时候
And it's set up so that when you change,
它能同步匹配转速 并进行补油
it spikes the engine revs so it surges when you change.
阿弥陀佛
Dear God!
这台车不只是绣花枕头
This body isn't just pretty,
它的设计能够最大程度地利用气流
it's been sculpted to maximise the air flowing over it
产生下压力
to generate down force
把车死死地摁在路上
to stick it to the road
奔驰制造过好几款黑色系列
There have been a number of Black Special Edition Mercs in the past
而且他们基本都很 无聊 真的 难以操控
and almost all of them have been, well, dreadful, really. Undriveable.
他们会产生过多扭矩 每当你踩下油门
They generated too much torque. So every time you put your foot down,
就会感觉车要自杀
it felt like they were trying to tear themselves apart.
你一路狂奔 它一路把小鸟
You'd be going along and it'd be sucking birds
大树 松鼠统统吸进发动机
and trees and squirrels into the engine
把蜿蜒的道路抛诸身后
and then ripping up the road and hurling chunks of tarmac out of the back
真的非常 扯淡
and it was just... They were ridiculous.
而在它身上 奔驰变聪明了
This, though, Mercedes has been clever
因为 虽然它比普通版的SLS的动力更强
because, yes, it generates more power than a standard SLS
但扭矩要小14Nm 所以现在
but 11 fewer torques. So now...
你踩下油门 它能将你的动作转化成速度
You put your foot down, it translates that action into speed,
而不是事故
not destructions.
欧 V8简直所向披靡
Oh, but you can't beat a V8!
我承认 V12确实很棒 但V8更赞
I mean, yes, a V12 is nice. But a V8 is nicer.
就这么简单
It just is.
我刚才说V8无懈可击
I'm just saying you can't beat a V8.
但我依然喜欢更强 更凶悍的V12
Oh, I like a 12, I do like a big powerful, slightly angry 12.
这车真不错
That's a great car, that.
就像 你轻轻戳它一下
It's......You just give it a little poke,
"对不起 请..."
"Excuse me, could you..."
太不可思议了
That is insane!
我乐翻了
I was very happy.
可就在此时 杰里米突然调转车头
And therefore a bit surprised when Jeremy suddenly veered off
来到了一个古老的意大利小镇
toward some old Italian town.
就是这里
There it is.
-什么 就这个 -是啊
- What? That? - Yeah.
这就是 罗密欧与朱丽叶里描写的那个阳台
That is the actual balcony from Romeo and Juliet.
-听我说 -干嘛
- Yeah. Couple of points. - What?
我开了台法拉利 晴空万里 身处意大利
I've got a Ferrari, it's a beautiful day, I'm in Italy.
你却来围观爱情故事里的阳台
You're looking at a balcony that was in a story... Story!
而且你说过自己讨厌这个故事的作者
Made up by a man who you said you don't like.
我讨厌莎翁 但你想...
I hate William Shakespeare but it's...Come on!
这是假的 只是个传说 编出来的
It's not real, it's a story. It was pretend.
你在畅游欧洲 要欣赏沿途名胜古迹
You're on a tour of Europe, you need to see stuff.
我开着法拉利游欧洲
I'm on a tour of Europe, in a Ferrari,
但现在却不在车里
except I'm not in a Ferrari,
站在一栋破房子外面瞻仰
I'm standing here Looking at an old building.
庆幸的是 一大波TG粉围观
Happily, a big crowd of Italian Top Gear fans then stopped him
于是我们放弃参观旧剧院 继续上路
from getting into some old theatre so we could get back on the motorway.
如果他接下来还停车看破房
If he's going to ruin this road trip
毁我的好心情 我就...
by stopping off to look at old things that don't move, I'll...
我早该记得
I should've remembered, of course,
哈蒙德是个没文化的粗人
Hammond isn't going to want to do anything cultural
而且还不懂得吃货的心理
and he isn't going to want to eat anything interesting.
感觉就像跟一个小板凳一起旅游一样
It's like travelling around with a garden chair.
我于是决定再耍他一下
I therefore decided to annoy him some more.
-哈蒙德 -怎么了
- Hammond? - What?
我们能从这里出去么
Shall we turn off here?
现在 为什么
What, now? Why would we?
因为我开腻了高速 想换个口味
Well, because I'm bored of driving on motorways, I want to go on other roads.
路边是不是又有一对破石头
Is there an old pile of bricks
或者门口供着一个仙女
or a gate that once featured in a fairy tale down here?
当然不是 只是开更有意思的路
No, no. It's driving but just on nice roads.
我绝不会去看韩塞尔与葛雷特的拎包
We're not going to look at Hansel and Gretel's handbag or something?
其实 我们正驶向意大利湖区
In fact, we were heading for the Italian Lakes,
我们此次行程皇冠上的明珠
a sparkling jewel in the golden crown of our perfect journey.
很快我发现 这些车和景
And soon I realised that cars like these on days like these
之前好像也拍过 DVD意大利任务的片头
have been used before, at the beginning of. The Italian job.
我知道这段路应该配什么音乐
I know just the music we need for this bit of our drive.
来一首蒙罗
Cue the Monro.
所有这些都很给力
Ooh, this is pretty,
开着我的意大利产超级GT 欣赏意大利美景
Looking at all of these Italian things from my Italian grand touring supercar.
我们唯一需要注意的是 进隧道时
We just have to be careful that if we go into a tunnel,
不要撞上推土机
we don't hit a bulldozer.
欧 这简直 欧
Oh, that's just... Oh!
爽歪歪
This is just magnificent.
但很快 我发现选择这里非常明智
But soon the real reason for turning off became apparent.
因为当道路越弯曲
As the roads became more twisty,
法拉利也越难以操控
the Ferrari was becoming more of a handful.
欧
Oh-ho! Oh!
你释放那730匹马力的时候需要谨慎一些
Uh, just need to be a bit careful about unleashing 730 brake horsepower.
它比F1赛车更强劲 我必须格外小心
It's actually more than an F1 car and I'm conscious of that right now.
救命啊
Help! Oh!
好险
Oh! Yeah.
我才不怕呢
I wasn't scared
法拉利比奔驰快这一点 我不置可否
I have no doubt that the Ferrari is faster than this
但奔驰更适合驾驶 因为它没那么恐怖
but this is just nicer to drive'cause it's less frightening.
在F12上 法拉利提供了所有你想要的
With the F12, Ferrari have given you everything you need
完美的操控
to have an incredible drive
或者给你一场严重车祸
or get yourself into a very great deal of trouble.
让一个赛车手来驾驶 他会说
Get a racing driver in this car and he will tell you,
"对 这才是一台车"
"Yes, that is a real car."
它不是用来停在高球停车场
It's not been tamed for people to park at the golf course
或者街边酒吧
and talk about in the bar.
你简直不敢相信它和普通SLS的差距
It's amazing how different this is to the standard SLS,
那车会动不动就甩尾
which would be wobbling its bottom all over everywhere.
但它不会 因为有电子差速器
This isn't because of its electronic differential.
你可以把它想象成保时捷GT3
You can think of it really like a Porsche GT3,
更轻 更硬 更专注 为赛道而生
lightened, hard, focused, on it, built for this.
这样一台SLS就像是
The SLS behaving like this is like
艾迪·伊扎德出演理查德三世
Eddie Izzard doing Richard III, it's...
想象一下 看一个哑剧演员扮演
It's almost weird to watch a pantomime character
心直口快 聪明伶俐的角色
become so straight.
诡异但不失智慧
Weird and yet brilliant.
最后 我们来到了旅店
Eventually, we reached our overnight halt
和我低调奢华有内涵的同事共进晚餐
and I went for supper with my cultured colleague.
你为什么说自己喜欢湖区
What do you mean you prefer the Lake District?
这里美得没边
Well, this is beautiful It is.
-而且我觉得... -比德文特湖还漂亮
- And to be honest, for me...
- More beautiful than Derwentwater.
加尔达湖都望尘莫及
Garda's not even the prettiest lake and look at it!
它太迷人 把镜头缩小到整个画面的75%
It's very lovely. Just scale it down to 75% of that
然后配上些雨水
and then introduce a bit of drizzle and...
-Keswick在湖区么 -当然
- Is Keswick in the Lake District? - Ooh, yeah.
但你在Keswick可吃不到这些 尝过没
What you don't get in Keswick are these. Have you had one?
-没 -吃个辣椒 来
- No. - Have a pepper. Eat.
快点 尝尝 你会喜欢的
Eat. Eat it. Go on, you'll like it.
真难吃
I don't like it.
后来 我们决定玩个老的游戏
Then we thought we'd play our favourite game.
他手里有一张法拉利的选配表
He's got the Ferrari options pricelist there
我来猜配件的报价
and I'm going to guess how much they cost.
这纸上有好多好多选装件
There are quite a Lot of options available.
比如
Pick some.
听好 碳纤维赛车座椅
Okay. Racing seats with carbon fibre.
不知道 600镑
I don't know, 600 quid?
5148镑
£5,184.
-我猜的有点低 -是啊
- I was a bit under. - Yeah.
轮胎上的碳纤维轮毂盖 就是 你懂的
But carbon fibre wheel caps, on the tyres, you know, on the...
-那个防尘盖 -对
- What, dust caps? - Yeah.
-碳纤维防尘盖 几个钱
Carbon fibre dust caps? Tenner.
480镑 挺便宜的
£480. I thought that was cheap.
-只是四个防尘盖 -是啊
- What, for four dust caps? - Yeah.
要480镑
£480?
杯架是不是标配
Are the cup holders standard?
你可以买一个碳纤维杯架
There is a carbon fibre cup holder you can get.
-杯架也碳纤维 -对啊 就是插杯子的地方
- A carbon fibre cup holder? - Yeah, you know, it pops in...
那个时候兰博基尼盖拉多的卖600镑
Well, they were £600 on a Lamborghini Gallardo a while back,
所以我猜一千左右
so I'LL go a thousand.
2112镑 你看 吓死你
£2,112. Yeah, this is amazing.
老实说 车本身算是最便宜的选择了
Really, the car is the cheapest option.
第二天 我们查了一下地图发现
The next day, we consulted a map and realised
自己差点赶上了F1赛历中最高速的比赛
we were just a spit from the fastest Grand Prix track on the calendar...
蒙扎
Monza.
速度圣殿
The Cathedral of Speed.
因为它的高速
Because it's so fast,
迫使我丢下了法拉利 鸟枪换炮
I've ditched the Ferrari and upped the ante
找来了帕加尼Huayra
to this Pagani Huayra,
也有一台V12 但加了两颗涡轮
still a V12 but now with two turbos.
在这里 你需要的是一颗导弹
Cause what you need here is a missile.
我选择了保时捷Cayman S
I've gone for a Porsche Cayman S.
-你疯了 -没有
- You're just being obtuse. - I'm not.
肯定疯了 搞了一台保时捷
You are. You've gone for a Porsche
却不是911 太气人了
so you can not go for a 911. It's just annoying.
它明显比911更厉害
This is better than a 911.
-怎么可能 当然911更快 -当然不是
- It isn't! A 911 is better than that. - It isn't.
-911的发动机在这里 -是的
- Because the 911 has its engine here. - Yes.
-但它是中置 -因为它不是911
- This is mid-engine. - Because it isn't a 911.
-不对 -它更好
- No! - It's better!
听着 如果我们在Cadwell公园或Lydden山
Listen, if we were driving around Cadwell Park, Lydden Hill...
-然后 -道路蜿蜒曲折 没错
- Yeah. - Nippy and fizzy, yes!
但这是在蒙扎 你需要动力
But not here at Monza. You need power.
你只是冲着这条
You're just hung up on this
-直得不能再直的直路来的 -当然
- great big long straight. - Yes.
但那后面一定会出现一个弯角
But there must be a corner down there somewhere,
否则你不可能从那里绕回来
otherwise you wouldn't be able to get down there again.
而且至少有两个弯角
There has to be......In fact there've got to be two corners.
-没错 至少有两个 -对
- Yes, genius, that's two corners. - Yeah.
有你的 但你可否知道
Brilliant. Do you know what?
帕加尼Huayra过弯能力非常非常强
The Pagani Huayra goes around corners really incredibly well.
你一定不敢相信它的攻弯速度
You will not believe how fast this goes around corners.
-Ok -灰常灰常牛逼
- Okay. - It's a lot better.
我确实不喜欢保时捷
It's true, I don't like Porches
也不喜欢开保时捷的人
and I don't much like the people who drive them,
尤其是那两个叫詹姆斯和理查德的
especially the ones called James and Richard.
我也不喜欢老款的Cayman
I didn't much like the original Cayman, either,
我称之为保时鸡
I called it the Cockster.
这台车也有一些不讨我喜欢的地方
And there are one or two things that I don't much like about this.
比如外形 我觉得它看上去太像911
The styling, for example, I think it looks too like a 911.
还有座椅 肩部空间太窄
And then there's the seats, the shoulder bolsters are too narrow.
如果你像我一样膀大腰圆
So, if you're broad-shouldered and hunky, like me,
会一直感觉空间狭小
you're getting sort of squashed all the time.
但剩下的一切绝对顶尖
However, the rest of it is absolutely sublime.
配上自适应悬架 整个驾乘
You've got these adaptive dampers, which means that it rides
操控 转向 都非常接近超级跑车
and handles and steers like the very best supercars.
但最棒的还是3.4升水平对置六缸发动机
But the best thing is the engine. A 3.4-litre flat six.
不会出现任何差错
There's just no thing about it that's wrong.
而且每时每刻 你都能听到
And all the time it makes this... You can hear that
深沉 喜人的声音
deep, reassuring noise,
像是把理查德·伯顿塞进了机舱里
it's like having Richard Burton in the boot,
无休止地抱怨你的发型
endlessly complimenting you on your hair
穿着 和驾驶风格
and your clothes and your driving style.
我的天 它太快了
Oh, my God! That is so fast!
我去
Oh, my God!
230, 240, 250,
每小时260公里
260 kilometres an hour.
270 妈呀
270! Oh, dear God.
简直吓尿了
Oh! I scared the crap out of myself then.
我勒个...
Holy sh...
太爽了
Oh, my God!
神车一台
What a machine!
蒙扎就是速度的象征
Monza is all about speed
而帕加尼Huayra则为风代言
and a Pagani Huayra is about that and very little else.
6.3升 V12 双涡轮
6.3-litre, v12, twin turbos.
超级强劲的动力
Truly, enormously powerful.
转向时宽胎产生巨大的抓地力
Turning in, immense grip from those fat tyres.
我有主动空气动力学 帮我紧贴赛道
I have aero, active aero keeping me planted on the track.
这些翼片都有着自己的作用
These things are built to work as well,
而不是单纯的装饰品
they're not some fragile trailer queen.
我驾驶的这台车跑了86,000公里
This car I'm in has done 86,000 kilometres.
而且我猜 这车可不好对付
And I'm guessing not many of them were gentle.
法拉利也许同样优秀 但还是不及Huayra
The Ferrari would've been good at this but not as good as the Huayra.
问题在于 哈蒙德快过头了
The problem is Hammond is going too fast,
没机会品味这条史诗般荣耀的赛道
he's not savouring this glorious, historical tracks.
他只能走马观花 狼吞虎咽
He's just wolfing it down, like a dog wolfs down a steak.
啊呜
(GOBBLES)
而我在做的则是细细咀嚼 享受着每一口
What I'm doing is masticating,
enjoying every mouthful.
杰瑞米开着错误的车在赛道上爬来爬去的时候
HAMMOND: As Jeremy crawled
round in his wrong car,
我在等着他回P房
I was waiting for him
to get back to the pits.
他要有好一会才能回来 是吧
He's going to be a while, isn't he?
趁他不在 来看看帕加尼的内饰
While he's gone, let me show you
the interior of the Pagani.
这绝对值得一看
It's worth seeing.
设计师们想让内饰很特别 我觉得他们做到了
They want it to feel special in here
and I think they've succeeded.
他们的确为此动了脑筋
They've really put thought into this,
making it feel special.
换档杆这里 所有的这些部分
This gear linkage here,
all these parts,
总共有67个组成零件
there's 67 components have gone
into making that
因而你能看见它是怎样工作的
in that skeleton form,
so you can see it working.
而用料方面也很实在
And the materials, too,
it's all genuine,
用了一大堆碳纤维 真皮 和铝制品
a lot of real carbon fibre,
real leather. And the aluminium,
你眼前的每一个铝制部件都不是铸造的
every single aluminium component
you can see in here isn't cast,
而是用一整块毛坯打磨而来
it's milled from a single piece,
a single billet, a lump of aluminium.
这些都让人感觉它值这个价
All of which means it feels
as expensive as it is.
我喜欢这车 那家伙还没回来呢吧
I like this car.
He's not back yet, is he?
这里是世界上唯一拥有两个lesbos弯的赛道
第一个很窄
This is the only track in the world with
two lesbos, the first one's quite tight,
而第二个 你可以尽情把车尾甩出
second one, though,
you can really hang your arse out
这里
There it is.
总共十二个气缸 咱们来数一数好消磨时光
It's 12 cylinders in total.
Let's count them, it'll pass the time.
一 二 我数的有点快了 不妨慢一点
One, two... Oh, I'm going too quickly,
might as well make it last.
三 哦等等
Three... Oh, hang on. Oh!
你现在一定觉得
You must be feeling now...
啥 你选错车了
- What?
- ...that you brought the wrong car.
恕我给你读点关于这车的评价
Let me read you something, if I may.
Talking about this.
这辆车在弯道里的平衡性接近完美
"The car's cornering balance
is near perfect,
油门的预见性很中立而且正确
"neutral but unerringly predictable
on a balanced throttle
它会稍稍转向不足
"and biased ever so slightly
towards understeer
若你是在前轮横向负载减轻前
"if you throttle up
before you begin easing
大脚给油的话
"the lateral load
out of the front tyres.
不是我说的 是Autocar杂志上写的
Not my words, the words of
Autocar magazine.
哇偶 可这到底什么意思啊
Wow! What do those words actually mean?
-我不知道 -我也是
-I've no idea.
-Me, neither.
不过我要再去跑跑
But I'm going to go back
out there now and throttle up
在出弯前猛然加速 看会发生什么
before I've eased the lateral load out
of the front tyres and see what happens.
好啊 我这就去
- Yeah!
- That's what I'm going to do.
我完全不懂那都啥意思
I have no idea what any of that means.
I haven't a clue.
来了 大脚油
Right! Throttle up.
噢 看见了没
Oh, now you see?
只是打个转而已
Now, that's just a spin.
看见了没 Autocar 这明明是转向过度
Now, you see, Autocar, that's oversteer.
有时候你读路试的文章会想 你丫到底在说啥
Sometime you read road tests and you
do think, "What are you on about?"
这是辆好车啊 你可以尽情的甩屁股
It's a really nice car
and you can get the arse out.
终于回来了
HAMMOND: Finally.
还装作玩得很开心吗 是的
-Still pretending to have fun?
-Yeah.
-额 屎粑粑会跟这差不多吗 -什么
- Will, uh, will Poo be like this?- Will what?
屎粑粑 当我们到那儿的时候
Poo, when we go there.
哦你是说Pau啊
Oh, Pau?
知道我最喜欢哪一段吗
Do you know my favourite bit?
恩恩
你可以
- HAMMOND: Yes. Yes.
- You could...
保时捷能像一条闪电一样划过那里
The Porsche through there,
it's just a streak of lightning.
没有车能比它更快
Nothing is faster than that.
没有车可以 那个弯也是
Nothing is.
Nothing's faster... Or through there.
你丫有点忘乎所以了吧 这辆小车是挺快
Yes, you're getting a bit carried away.
It's fast. It's a quick little car.
说实话它在这块跑更合适点
To be honest,
it's more at home in this bit here.
你能从商店门口飞奔过去
You could "Oh, look!" past the shops
然后喊 那有个学校还有个超市
and "Oh, there's a school
and a supermarket."
这才是你的车该出现的地方 不是这里
And that's really where it belongs.
Not here.
你错了 我没错
- You're wrong.
- I'm not wrong.
哈蒙德我可以跟你赌任何东西 保时捷在这开得更快
Hammond, I bet you anything you like
that around here the Porsche is faster.
杰瑞米这也太
Jeremy, that's...
好吧好吧
输的人要这样说
- Okay!
- Whoever loses has to say,
我爱詹姆斯梅
"I love James May."
必须要对着镜头说
They have to say that
on television to a camera.
好啊
Fine.
肯定会是你对着镜头说 我爱詹姆斯梅的
You actually have to go up to the camera
and go, "I love James May."
好啊我倒希望看着你这么说
All right. Well, I look forward
to hearing you say it.
哦这原来叫lesmos
Oh, they're lesmos.
我以为这里是lesbo 其实是lesmo
I thought there was lesbo one and...
It's lesmo...
Martin Brundle念的时候一定是感冒了
Martin Brundle must have had a cold.
走你
Right.
3 2 1 出发(意大利语）
出发
And we are away.
打哈欠中
天哪这简直太尴尬了
Oh, God! This is just embarrassing
这样虐他连点成就感都没有
because where's going to be my sense of
achievement when I thrash him?
对车来说有个问题
CLARKSON: There is a point with cars
当他们变得马力很强 跑得很快的时候
where they become
so powerful and so fast
他们也会很疯狂很吓人
they become too hectic
and too frightening.
这也是怀亚所存在的问题
That's the problem with the.Huayra.
正在过第一个lesmo弯
Through the first of the lesmo corners,
as it turns out.
我知道这听起来很二
CLARKSON: I know it sounds silly
but once you go
但是当你开一辆五百多匹的车时 你反而会更慢
beyond 500-550 horsepower,
you end up driving the car more slowly.
很奇怪不过真的是这样的
It's weird but it's true.
用拎着刀去跟枪斗来形容这场比赛
Never has there beem
a more stark example of
真是再合适不过了
bringing a knife to a gunfight.
而开保时捷 我在任何地方都可以全油门
The Porsche, around here,
I'm absolutely pinning it everywhere.
这难不倒我 一点也不吓人 简单得很
It doesn't worry me,
it's not frightening, it's easy.
而那辆车
That thing, though...
我们会见证的
Well, we shall see.
我说的会被证实 他则会说 我爱詹姆斯梅
My case will be proven and he will be
saying, "I love James May."
我看到了那里显示着270KM/H
That's 270 I saw there.
他不会看到这个数字的
He won't see anything like that.
哦
Oh.
我听到了一个小矮人正在接近
I hear the sound of
an approaching midget.
马力全开
Fully on the power.
准备
Ready, steady...
冲线啦
And across the line!
2分14秒8
Two minutes, 14.8.
我们称之为2分15
We'll call it 2:15.
接下来轮到卡门了
Then it was the Cayman's turn.
意大利语
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
说实话 这样比一点意思都没有
Really, I am taking no pleasure in this.
但是他需要好好地上一课
But he does need to learn a lesson,
你不能仅仅因为你喜欢这辆车
that you can't just go making
stupid claims about a car
就大放厥词
just 'cause you like it.
说实话 那玩意儿的圈速
我甚至可以用煮蛋计时器来测
No, seriously, that thing round...
I could be using an egg timer.
他难道觉得能靠技术把时间补回来
How does he imagine he can
possibly make up enough time?
无论他觉得自己有多厉害
No matter how good
he thinks he is in it.
很明显 绝对不会赢的 管他呢
Clearly, it's not going to... Anyway.
说啥呢
老大
- You what?
- Mate!
你你你怎么不
Where... Why aren't you...
我没说是我开啊
I didn't say I'd be driving it.
我靠 那是谁
Well, who is?
有人说是试替哥 确实是他
Well, some say it's The Stig, and it is.
你有说过必须是我开吗 没说过
Did you at any point say
I had to drive it? No.
你有说过你要用试替哥吗
Did you at any point say
you were going to use The Stig?
你为啥不用呢
Why would you not?
因为我认为 在每条定义
Because I think
in every possible definition,
每项规则里 这都算作弊
in every set of rules, it's cheating.
他回来了
Oh, here he is.
2分13秒2
HAMMOND: 2:13:2.
是的
- 2:13:2.
- Yes.
你跑了2分14秒8 差了一秒
You were 2:14:8. So he's one point...
这么说来 女士们先生们 保时捷正如我所说
So, there you are, ladies and gentlemen,
the Porsche is, as I said,
比怀亚更快
faster than the, uh...Huayra.
因此它才是更明智的选择
And therefore was a more
sensible choice of car.
-不不不 是试替哥比我快 -咋了
- No. The Stig is faster than me.
- What?
而试替哥比谁都快 这是他存在的意义
But The Stig is faster than everyone,
that's the point of The Stig,
否则他会炸掉的
if he wasn't he'd explode.
我们开着奔驰和法拉利离开蒙扎的时候
CLARKSON: As we left Monza
in the Mercedes and the Ferrari,
气氛有点阴沉
the mood was glum.
这是作弊
It's cheating.
然而第二天早上看到过夜的小镇的名字时
CLARKSON: The next morning, however,
Hammond cheered up
哈蒙德就开心起来了
when he discovered the name of the town
where we'd stayed the night.
偷笑中
从胸罩镇前往法国的路上
From Bra to the French Riviera,
我们本可以走高速公路
we could've used the motorway.
但是我们决定要改走一条
But we decided instead
世界上最美妙的
to use the finest switchback roads
曲折的小路
in the world.
这意味着要扔掉奔驰
This meant ditching the Mercedes
和法拉利
and the Ferrari
而选这两个小家伙来代替
and opting for these instead.
在这样子的路上
On a road like this,
你需要一辆小车 一辆掀背小钢炮
you need something small,
you need a hot hatchback.
如果你想要一辆掀背小钢炮的话
And if you're going to get
a hot hatchback,
为什么不选钢炮之王 就这辆
why not get the king? This one.
高尔夫GTI
The Golf GTI.
我很爱第1代
I loved the Mk1
16气门的第2代也不赖
and the 16-valve Mk2 wasn't bad, either.
但是后来的版本 它们虽然也不错
But since then...
I mean, they weren't bad
但是仿佛失去了魔力一般
but the magic went missing.
而在这辆第七代上 魔力又回来了
With this one, though, the Mk7,
it is back.
这辆车是全能型的
This car can do everything.
装配质量不错 价格合理
It's well made, it's sensibly priced.
很经济环保 配置也不错
It's economical, it's well-equipped.
能坐五个人 有个大后备箱
It seats five, it's got a big boot.
但是抛开这些不谈
But strip all that away and underneath,
本质上它就是一辆小钢炮
its DNA is hot hatchery.
2升涡轮增压引擎 220匹
Two-litre turbo engine, 220 horsepower
没有任何扭矩转向
and no torque steer.
瞧着 大脚油过这个发卡弯
Now, watch this. Foot hard down,
going around a hairpin bend.
太让人惊讶了
It's just astonishing.
这车的前差速器好的让人难以置信
The front diff on this is beyond belief.
哇偶 天哪太棒了
Whoa! God, this is good.
他又选错车了
He's got it wrong again.
高尔夫GTI 确实不错
The Golf GTI, it's a brilliant car,
它或许是最好的全能型车
it's probably the best all-rounder
in the world.
但是 重点就在这
But that's... That's the point,
你不需要全能型车
an all-rounder is exactly
what you don't need.
全能不可避免的意味着要处处妥协
An all-rounder
is inevitably compromised.
我只需要掀背钢炮的本质
I just want pure distilled
essence of hot hatch.
那就只有一个选择了
And that means only one thing right now.
嘉年华ST
The Fiesta ST.
当福特设计这辆车的时候 他们只是把零件拼到一起
When Ford put this car together,
they assembled all the right bits
然后想 恩 我估计这样挺好
and thought, "Yeah, I reckon
that would be good."
我觉得他们恐怕估计不到
I don't think they could
possibly have known
这车到底有多好
quite how good
it was going to turn out to be,
因为这车太出乎人意料了
because it's astonishing.
这车的确不如高尔夫马力大
It's down on power
compared to the Golf, yes.
但是它更小 更钢炮
But it's smaller, that's more hot hatch.
更轻
And it's lighter,
意味着马力重量比基本上和高尔夫一样了
which means the power-to-weight ratio
is pretty much the same.
另外这辆车还敏捷的很
And it's beyond nimble.
过弯时如果随意一点的话
You start to just take
liberties with it.
走线故意放宽一点
Deliberately running a line
a little bit wide,
你就能享受把它拉回来的乐趣了
so you get the pleasure
of turning it back in.
太美妙了
It's superb.
这是世界上最棒的开心方向盘
It's the biggest grin-maker
I think the world has ever seen.
到达下一个村子的时候 不可避免的
In the next village, though, inevitably
杰瑞米决定我们应该吃点什么
Jeremy decided we should
get something to eat.
你咋不吃饭呢
Why aren't you eating your lunch?
我不喜欢意面
I don't like pesto.
什么 我不喜欢吃意面
- What?
- I don't like pesto.
为啥不喜欢 就是不喜欢
- Why not?
- It's just bits.
还有另一个停下来的理由
CLARKSON: There was, however,
a very good reason why we'd stopped.
你得说出来 你打赌输了 必须说出来
You've got to say it.
You lost the bet, you've got to say it.
我才不说
I'm not saying it.
你必须说
You've got to say it.
我正大光明的打败了你 保时捷就是更快
I beat you fair and square.
The Porsche was faster.
-一点也不公平 你丫作弊 -快说
- It wasn't fair. You cheated.
- Say it.
啥
What?
James May
...James May.
-这样行了吧 -不 要说清楚
-There.
-No. Say it so it's audible.
我爱James May
I... love James May.
这事办妥了以后我们又上路了
CLARKSON: With that done,
we got back in our cars.
当提到美国公路旅行的时候你会想到
纪念碑谷地
When you think of an American road trip,
you think of Monument Valley,
那条路笔直通向远方
that road spearing off
into the distance.
这条路就相当于欧洲的纪念碑谷
Well, this is Europe's equivalent
of Monument Valley.
这可能是目前这趟旅途中我最喜欢的一段了
This might just be my favourite bit
of our trip so far.
好车配美景
The car, the place.
怎一个完美了得
This is perfect.
上帝创造这边地方的目的
When God was making
this part of the world,
就是为了小钢炮
这条路就是为小钢炮量身定制的
it was for hot hatchbacks.
That's what it's for.
然而很不幸
Unfortunately, however,
我们激情的下山之旅被迫停止
our headlong charge down the Alps
因为我们已经无路可走
was halted because we ran out of land.
-嗯 -啥
- Mmm, that.
- What?
那就是传说中的蒙地卡罗
如果在那里开着大众和福特
Well, it's Monte-Carlo.
If we drive into there
我们会被当作流浪汉被抓起来
in a Volkswagen and a Ford,
they'll arrest us for vagrancy.
有道理哦
That's a good point.
-你可以是个军火贩子 -是
- I mean, you can be an arms dealer...
- Yeah.
但你不能开着一辆嘉年华在里面转悠
...but you can't drive around
in a Fiesta.
-这是底线 -我们得换车了
- There's a limit.
- We're going to need to switch.
这是我们为了显摆而换的车
For posing,
these were the cars we selected.
哈蒙德的兰博基尼 Aventador Roadster
A Lamborghini Aventador Roadster
for Hammond
和我的布加迪威龙
and a Bugatti Veyron for me.
这可不是一般的威龙
Now, this is no ordinary Veyron,
这可是 Grand Sport Vitesse 版本的
this is the Grand Sport Vitesse.
8升 4凸轮轴 W16发动机
Eight-litre, quad-cam W16.
极速404km/h
Top speed 251 miles an hour
还是没车顶的
with no roof.
这里就是这车该待的地方
Here it is in its natural habitat.
现在是2档
出发后第一次
I'm in second gear.
I'm now using second gear
上2档
for, well, the first time
since I set off.
又回到1档了
And back down to first.
很奇妙的一点是这里的人们在十点钟
It is extraordinary that here men get up
从单身公寓中醒来
from their bachelor pads at about 10:00,
然后开着用逃税的钱买的车
get into their cars that they bought
using money they should have paid in tax
花上一整天的时间
and then spend all day
在这里一圈一圈地转
driving round and round
and round in circles.
真是难以理解
Why?
人们看着我开着橙色的兰博基尼 Aventador Roadster
People see me in my orange
Lamborghini Aventador Roadster
觉得我肯定是个有钱有势的土豪
and think, "Yes.
There's a man of potency and wealth."
但是两秒钟之后
当他们看到那辆布加迪
And then two seconds later,
they see that Bugatti Veyron
他们肯定会想 来了一个更大的土豪
and think, "There's a richer,
more powerful man."
伙计很抱歉
I'm sorry about this, mate,
你又一次选错车了
but once again,
you're in the wrong car.
我对 再一次 表示异议
I take issue with the "once again"
只不过 这是有史以来第一次 我选错了车
but, yes, for the first time,
I've got the wrong car.
压根没人在看你 一个都没有
Nobody is looking at you,
nobody.
如果我花了29万英镑买了辆兰博基尼
If I had spent 290,000
在摩纳哥里面开
on a Lamborghini to drive around Monaco
而你却开着那玩意
and you turned up in that,
我恨不得开车撞墙
I'd just drive this into a wall.
这是世界上最势利的地方了
This is the snobbiest place on earth.
这里使
It makes...
这里让洛杉矶看上去如同朝鲜
It makes Los Angeles
look like North Korea.
当你要让别人代客泊车的时候
And this snobbery is an issue
这种势利就变成了个问题
when you try to
get your car valet parked.
现在的问题是
这哥们开着最便宜的法拉利
The problem is that chap has just
turned up outside the Hotel de Paris
加利福尼亚
in a Ferrari California.
来到巴黎大饭店门口
The cheapest Ferrari there is.
尽管如此 他依然很喜欢他的车
Nevertheless, he likes it very much.
是啊 这车确实不错
所以它就停在酒店门口了
Yeah, and it's nice.
And as a result, it's there.
-就因为这是辆好车 -是的
- Okay? 'Cause it looks good.
- Yeah.
但是一分钟内
But in a minute,
一个哈萨克斯坦的军火贩子
就会开着一辆更好的车停到这里
a Kazakhstani arms dealer
is going to arrive in a nicer car
然后这辆法拉利就会被开走
and the Ferrari
is going to be taken away
被停到城市另一头的立体停车场里
and put in a multi-storey
on the other side of Monaco.
但是我们
HAMMOND: But we pull up there
开着布加迪威龙和Aventador
in a Bugatti Veyron and
a Lamborghini Aventador Roadster,
你是说会有比这俩还牛的车出现
are you're saying something better
is going to come along than that?
我保证在蒙地卡罗
In Monte-Carlo, I promise you,
有人会开着企业号飞船出现
someone would turn up
in the USS Enterprise
然后我们的车就会被扔进立体停车场
and our cars would be
in the multi-storey.
车有多好一点也不重要
It doesn't matter how good your car is,
停车员总会把车开走的
the valet parkers will ultimately
take it away
因为没有最好只有更好
because something better always arrives.
一定会有解决方案的
这是一次完美的公路旅行
There's got to be a way around this.
This is the perfect motoring trip.
所以我们的目标是
在这次完美公路之旅中
So we go and check in there, in a car,
-开着一辆车到这酒店并入住 -嗯
- on our perfect road trip...
- Yeah.
要求我们第二天早上出来的时候
车还停在原地不动
...we come out in the morning,
it's still there.
这就是我们的挑战
That's our challenge.
一定会相当特别
It's going to have to be pretty special.
哦耶
Oh, yeah.
然而哈蒙德却选择了
Hammond, however, opted to go
世界上销量最好的车型之一
with one of the best-selling cars
the world has ever seen.
福特T型车
A Model T Ford.
但却有个棘手的问题
And straightaway there was a problem.
我们不会开这辆车
We didn't know how it worked.
好 等一下
Right, now, look.
让我们把东西理清楚
Let's list the things.
这有三个踏板
There are... There's three pedals.
你怎么 换挡杆在哪 这是换挡杆吗
How do you... Where's the gear?
Is this the gear? That's...
哦 如果 我踩的这个不是离合器
HAMMOND: Oh, if it's......
I haven't got my foot on the clutch.
-那不是离合器-好吧
- That isn't the clutch.
- Well, then...
哪个是油门
Which one's the accelerator?
这是油门
我们确定油门不是在踏板上
That's the accelerator.
It isn't a pedal, I'm sure...
这我怎么踩得到
How am I going to get my foot up there?
额 那是干啥的
好吧 让我们来启动发动机
- Um... What's that do?
- Right, well, start it.
这才不是启动按钮呢
- That's not the starter!
最终哈蒙德成功发动了
Eventually,
Hammond did make it begin.
但是那时我们才发现他不知道如何刹车
But then we learned
he didn't know how to make it stop.
看看这个是干啥的
Oh, now what have I done?
我们越开越快了
We're going faster!
那不是手刹
快停下
That's not the handbrake.
Stop it. Stop it.
快停下来
- Stop it now!
好的 向前开
Right, forwards.
-等等 准备好了 -向前开
- Hang on. Now, ready.
- Forwards.
-这可不是向前啊 -完全不是
- That's not forwards.
- No, it's not at all, is it?
快停下了
Stop it. Make it stop.
你造吗 这车一点也不想停下来
It doesn't really want to, do you know?
快停下
Make it stop!
额 杰里米 我们阻碍了整个摩纳哥的交通
Uh, Jeremy, we've held up Monaco.
-是吗 -你自己看
- Have we?
- Look.
额滴神啊
Oh, God.
然而很快我就接近目的地了
Soon, however,
we were nearing our destination.
哈蒙德啊 我一般很少这样说
It's not often I say this, Hammond,
但你真是太天才了
but you have been a genius.
你从没这样夸过我
You have never said that.
因为如果我们都不会开这个车
Because if we can't drive this,
巴黎大饭店的停车员
又有多大几率能开走这车呢
what chance do the valet parkers
at the Hotel de Paris have?
不可能开走
这是我干过最难的事情了
None, it's the hardest thing
I've ever done.
他们会想移走这辆车却无能为力
They'll want to move this
but they won't be able to.
你好 先生
- Bonjour, monsieur.
- Hello, sir.
熄火
Shut it down.
交给你了
All yours.
你好
- Bonjour.
Bonjour.
那么停车员们能成功吗
So, would the valet staff
be successful?
很显然他们失败了
No.
论如何打败专职停车员
So, there we go.
That is how to beat the valet parkers.
买一辆他们不会开的车
Buy a car they can't drive.
嗯 但是问题是
Yes, but the problem is
今天我们要驾车
today we are going
从蔚蓝海岸到Saint-Tropez
down the French Riviera to Saint-Tropez
我可不想
and I'm not sure
开着这车去那里
I want to go in that.
我到哪也不想开这车
I'm not sure
I'd actually go anywhere in It.
这是一辆捷豹E-Type
This is a Jaguar E-Type.
1962年I系列敞篷版
It's a 1962 Series 1 Roadster
配有美妙的3.8升直六发动机
with the proper 3.8-litre straight six.
而且这可不是一般的1962年E-Type
And it's not just any 1962 E-Type.
这辆车就是我的
It's mine.
我找不到有比这车
And I can think of no car
更加适合这样完美的一天
more perfect for a day like today.
谁说的 我可以
Oh, I can.
因为我开的是一辆V8的F-Type
Because I am in a V8 F-Type.
这比哈蒙德的E-Type更快
This is faster than Hammond's E-Type.
更舒适 更经济 更可靠
It's more comfortable,
more economical, more reliable,
还有空调哦
more air-conditioned
即使要价86,000英镑
And even though it costs Ј86,000,
也比E-Type便宜
it's cheaper.
法国佬 起床啦
Wake up, Frenchies.
哦 这浪声
Oh, that's a racket.
你能听见这后面的浪声吗
Can you hear the exhausts
from back there?
声音大的在威尼斯都听得到
They can hear them back in Venice.
此时此地开着这辆车
Never has a car been more
perfectly tailored to its environment
我想不到有比这更完美的组合了
than this is here.
这就是土豪阶层的发源地
This is where the jetset was invented.
我能感受到我们身处一个捷豹的世界
We are in Jag country, I can feel it.
餐厅的账单上不可能几十年不被结账
Not a restaurant bill will have been
paid around here for decades.
只有捷豹的轮胎印能够证明他们的去处
Just Jaguar tyre marks
where they've screeched away.
对不起 我开回去拿我的钱包
"I'm sorry.
I'll pop off and get my wallet."
在70年代有个电视剧
There used to be
a TV series in the '70s
叫做The Persuaders
由Roger Moore和Tony Curtis饰演
called The Persuaders!
with Roger Moore and Tony Curtis.
我正在听这电视剧的主题曲
And I'm hearing that music now.
Roger Moore和Tony Curtis
Roger Moore, Tony Curtis,
开着法拉利Dino和阿斯通马丁DBS在这里穿梭
whizzing about down here
in a Ferrari Dino
在这里来回穿梭
and an Aston Martin DBS,
解决各式各样的问题
solving many things,
比如英雄救美
punching men and saving womens.
我也正在享受这个美妙的时刻 直到
I was enjoying it too.
Until...
哈蒙德 毕加索博物馆就在前面
Hammond, the Picasso museum's
along here.
我们可以停下来进去瞧瞧
We could stop and have a look.
有必要吗 我可开着一辆捷豹呢
Really? I'm in a Jaguar,
在法国南部开着我的E-Type
my E-Type, in the south of France,
你却要我停下来参观一个
and you want me stop driving
to look at a man
耳朵长错地方的男人
whose ears are in the wrong place?
错了 你说的是梵高
No, that was Van Gogh.
毕加索是那个
Picasso's the one who puts eyes
把眼睛放错边的人
on the wrong side of somebody's head.
来嘛 这是趟公路旅行
我们来看点画作
Come on, it's a road trip.
Let's look at some pictures.
你自己听听你刚才说了啥
Did you not hear
what you just said?
这是一场公路之旅 我们去看画画吧
"It's a road trip.
Let's look at some pictures."
不能这样！
No!
你为什么如此没文化？
Oh, why are you so uncultured?
在朱昂莱班 一个所有女孩
In Juan-les-Pins,
where all the girls have
都特意穿着裸胸泳衣
carefully designed topless swimsuits
圈养赛马也是仅供娱乐 的地方
and racehorses they keep just for fun,
为博一笑 哈哈哈
for a laugh, a-ha-ha.
我们停了下来 让哈蒙德能看点吃的
we pulled over so Hammond could look at some food.
-现在又咋了？ -我不喜欢章鱼
- What now?
- I don't like octopus.
章鱼怎么惹你了？
What's the matter with it?
-额.. -你想试试我的松露煎蛋卷吗？
- Well...
- Do you want my truffles on an omelette?
不喜欢松露 你毁了我的旅行
Don't like truffles.
You are ruining this trip for me.
-继续 -每次我们停下来吃饭
- Go on.
- Every time we stop for food,
-你就逼我吃章鱼 -很好吃！
- you make me eat octopus...
- It's nice!
或是螃蟹眼睛 蜗牛腿
...or crab's eyes or snail's legs.
而每次我们一上路 你就又想停下来
And then every time we get going again,
you make us stop again
看一堆砖头还有什么故事里的阳台
to Look at a pile of bricks
and then that balcony from a story.
这是一场公路之旅
It's a road trip.
我们要看风景 瞧瞧我带你来的地方
We're supposed to be seeing...
Look what I've brought you to.
在路上
On the road.
我带你来的是我最喜欢的餐厅之一
I've brought you to one of my favourite restaurants.
-海边的双人餐桌 -不是..
- A table for two by the waterside...
- It's not...
吃了它
Eat it.
-这可不是舌尖上的旅行啊 -快吃
- Not an eating trip, is it?
- Eat it.
-把章鱼吃掉 -它刚动了
- Eat the octopus.
- It moved.
不会的 这只是它其中的一只腿
It didn't. It's only one of its legs.
我..
I...
难道你想在服务区
Would you like to stop
at a service station
吃薯片？
and get some crisps?
午餐后 我们去了海滨散步
After lunch, we went
for a stroll along the seafront
看风景
to look at the sights.
但因为这是一档老少咸宜的节目
But because this is a family show,
我们不能展示看的是何种风景
we can't show you
what those sights were.
然而最终 我们手里的冰激凌化得一点不剩
Eventually, though,our ice creams melted completely
所以我们继续上路
so we set off.
你知道 我们在讨论完美公路之旅
You know we were talking about the perfect road trip?
幸好没有开兰博基尼和布加迪来这里
How wrong would the Lamborghini
and Bugatti have been here?
也没有开福特嘉年华
Or the Ford Fiesta.
是呀
Yeah.
问题在于 当我们到达圣特拉斐
The problem is that when we arrived in Saint-Raphael,
交通状况正如预期
the traffic was predictable.
E-Type也是
And so was the E-Type.
哈蒙德的车听上去很虚弱
Hammond's car is sounding poorly.
哦 天啊
Oh, God.
它能挺过圣特鲁佩斯的堵车吗？
Will it be able to do the traffic jam into Saint-Tropez?
嗯..
Um...
老实讲 我真的
I'm honestly... I'm really...
我真的很担心它 我说真的
I am worried about her,
actually, I really am.
是吗？
Are you?
哦天啊 听起来真不咋地
Oh, God, that doesn't sound right.
60年代的英国好声音
The sound of Britain in the '60s.
嘠叽嘎叽嘎叽
Ding-ding-ding-ding-ding...
为中部的制造业而自豪
"Made in the Midlands with pride.
是我们造出了这么漂亮的车
"Ah, we've really put this together
very nicely, we have, very nice.
我们的E-Type做的很好
"Done a good job with that E-Type, we have."
量油尺太烫了 不能摸
Ow, dipstick's too hot, can't touch that.
-噢 -理查德
- Oh. - Richard.
-干嘛 -我带了点东西给你
- What?
- I've bought you something
让你高兴起来
to cheer you up.
-是吗？ -一个小礼物
- Have you?
- It's a little present.
呵呵
Is it?
一个渔网
It's a fishing net.
我知道这不是E-Type的作风
I know it's not the same as an E-Type
但现在它不行了 你可以用这个
but now this doesn't work any more,
you can have that.
谢谢你的渔网
Thank you for my fishing net.
只要3欧元 比这车值钱
It's three Euros,which is more than this is worth.
对现在来说
Now.
我有一个主意
I then had an idea.
我们从这里到圣特鲁佩斯来一场比赛
We'll have a race from here to Saint-Tropez
但我们要过夜的 对吧？
but we'll stay the night, yes?
-比赛 -什么意思..
- A race. - What...
不
No.
-别管这些车了 -丢弃捷豹
- Ditch these. - Ditch the Jags.
你也没得选
You've got no choice.
新酒店叫什么名字？巴黎大饭店
What's that new hotel called?Hotel de Paris.
-那有一个天台露天酒吧 -好的
- It's got a rooftop bar.
- Okay.
后到的人
Last one there
要穿一件写着"我爱龟速船长"的衬衫
has to wear an "I love James May" T-shirt
明天一整天
tomorrow, all day.
真是不小的一个处罚啊 但是..
That's quite a forfeit but, um...
好呀
Yeah.
我有一条妙计
I have had such a brilliant idea
克拉克森必输无疑
that Clarkson has had it.
因为我将驾驶这车去往圣特鲁佩斯
Because I am going to Saint-Tropez on this.
杜卡迪
The Ducati Diavel.
暗黑
Dark.
-准备就绪 哈蒙德？ -随时待命
- Are you ready, Hammond?
- Yeah.
倒计时 三
In three,
二  一
two, one...
出发！
Go!
好了
All right.
我有很好的理由选这车
I chose this bike for a very good reason.
引擎1200cc V型双缸
The engine, 1200cc V-twin,
源自杜卡迪赛车1198
taken from a Ducati sports bike,the 1198.
相信我 杜卡迪知道如何制造快车
And Ducati, trust me, know a thing
or two about making fast bikes.
162匹马力 英国版本
162 brake horsepower, the UK edition.
在法国 被限制在100
Restricted in France to 100.
但是你知道吗?
But you know what?
但对付我今天的任务是绰绰有余了
That's still going to be plenty
for what I want to do today.
极速170
Top speed about 170,
0到60mph加速2.5秒
0-60 about two and a half,
你懂的 和布加迪威龙一样
you know, the same as a Bugatti Veyron.
又堵了 你看
Traffic, you see?
他怎么可能摆平这一切?
How's he going to get to even this?
他永远都开不出去
He's never even going to
get out of town.
我看起来很帅 车又是风驰电掣
I Look cooL. It goes Like the clappers.
克拉克森就在这了
Clarkson's had it here.
好了 看到没 没车了
There you go. See that? Clear!
你好
Hello.
你看到的是一辆菲尔兰 Squadron78游艇
You join me on a Fairline Squadron 78.
就是说78英尺长
That's 78 feet long.
这台机器的引擎让人难以置信
The engines in this thing are unbelievable,
32升 两只涡轮增压的V12
32-litre, twin turbocharged V12s.
走起
Here we go.
你可以这么开
And you can drive it like this.
或这样
Or like that.
因为这是一艘船
And because it's a boat
我可以横穿海湾抵达圣特鲁佩斯
I could get to Saint- Tropez across the bay.
然而哈蒙德不得不绕过海湾
Whereas Hammond had to go all the way round it.
穿行在车流中
Sneaking through,sneaking through, just.
每一辆车
Every car counts.
任何一辆都可能是克拉克森
Any one of these could be Clarkson.
他在哪？
Where is he?
如果我超过了他
If I have been past him,
他只能看我裹在皮衣里的屁屁感叹
he would have been looking at my bottom in leather, going,
"哦 看 穿皮裤的男人屁屁" 他就好这口
"Oh, look, a man's bottom in leather."
He's obsessed with it.
我不知道理查德哈蒙德在开什么
I don't know what Richard Hammond is using,
但我猜
but I'm guessing
是一辆摩托车之类的
it's a motorcycle of some sort.
所以他会从头到脚都是裹着牛皮
So he'll be dressed from head to foot in leather,
恼火于交通堵塞
furious at the traffic,
屁股这样..
with his bottom...
看看我啊 我在开摩托车
"Look at me, I'm on a motorbike.
跨下一个震动的机器
"I'm straddling a throbbing machine!"
我才不会那么做
I'm not doing any of that.
导航带我们驶向圣特鲁佩斯
Got the satnav down here to bring us
onto the bearing of Saint-Tropez.
我还想再快一点
I'm just going to take it up
a little bit more,
2300转
2,300 rpm a side.
你瞧呀 看看这个！
Look at this. Look at this now!
吃我的柴油吧 哈蒙德
Eat my diesel, Hammond!
我只想弯过一个转角
I just want to come round
one of these corners
看见一辆迈凯轮12C
and see a McLaren 12C.
或者 SLS黑色系
Or an SLS Black.
而且被堵的死死的 然后我超过他
And he will be stuck. And I will pass him.
我要问问他 "摩托车
And I will ask him, "Mmm, bikes.
还不够好?"
"Still no good?"
你们有人要喝点吗？
Anyone fancy a drink in the crew?
-要不要？ -好
- Yeah? - Yeah.
不好意思
Excuse me.
非常谢谢
Thanks very much.
又堵车了 又堵车了
Standing traffic. Standing traffic.
来吧 克拉克森 你在哪?
Come on, Clarkson, where are you?
这要没人突然打开门或者左转
As long as nobody opens their door
or suddenly turns left,
我就可以一直这样飚下去
I can just keep hacking through it like this.
你瞧 这就有个开门的
Oh, there you go. That's the door open.
就这一个
That's the one.
总有人会这样 总有一个
That's the fella. There's always one.
他会在任何这些车里 我随时都可能看见他
He's going to be in any one of these. Any minute now I'm going to see him.
这肯定是他了
This has got to be him.
女士们先生们 你好 杰里米·克拉克森
Ladies and gentlemen, hello, Jeremy Clarkson.
不对 不是他
No. That's not him.
当Squadron正卯足了劲前进
With the Squadron at full chat
圣特鲁佩斯近在咫尺
and Saint-Tropez very close indeed,
船上的时光也美好极了
life on the boat was good.
咕噜噜！
Grunt!
这让它更像一辆杜卡迪了
This is more like it.
不断地前行中
Getting a proper move on.
解决了最差劲的圣拉斐尔的交通
Having cleared the worst of the Saint-Raphael traffic,
我现在正飞速行驶在开阔的道路上
I was now on the open road
and closing fast.
好吧 老实讲
Okay, there is, I'll be honest,
只有很小很小的可能性
a tiny, tiny chance
他从堵塞的交通中开出城市
he got through all of that traffic and out of town
然后在这里横扫千军万马
and then caned it along here
而我还没赶上他
and I simply haven't caught him yet.
但我有理由相信
But I've got a good suspicion
等我们到达圣特鲁佩斯
when we get to Saint-Tropez,
那儿交通会更糟 我就能找到他了
there'll be more traffic
and that is where I'll find him.
我要将78英尺长的船泊入圣特鲁佩斯港口
I'm about to park my 78-foot boat in Saint-Tropez harbour.
这是我唯一的劣势
This is the only slow bit,
进港太慢
the wobbling about
in Saint-Tropez harbour.
因为他们有个傻X的限速
'Cause they've got some stupid speed limit.
哦 天啊 看哪
Oh, good God, Look at this.
堵得水泄不通
Traffic. That's a big jam.
喔!
Oh!
见缝插针 过过过
Squeezing through, coming through,
coming through.
当哈蒙德还在
As Hammond weaved his way
圣特鲁佩斯常年的堵车中挣扎
through the annual Saint-Tropez traffic jam...
哦 我天啊
Oh, my God.
我正在等待被安排一个泊位
I was still waiting to be given a parking space.
过了 过了
Through, coming through, coming through.
巴黎大饭店 谢谢你
Hotel de Paris, I thank you.
兄弟!
Mate!
你怎么样?
How are you?
你怎么...
How...
天啊 你流了好多汗
God, you look sticky.
怎么特么可能?
How the bloody hell?
我没看见你啊 我一次都没有看到你
I didn't see you.I didn't see you once.
我看到了一台F12 我以为是你
I saw a Ferrari F12,I thought it was you.
问题是
Thing is
你只有摩托车驾照
you've got a motorcycle licence.
-是 -而哥手里
- Yes. - Well, now, I have
有游艇驾照
a boat Licence.
当然这就意味着明天嘛
And what this means, of course,is tomorrow,
你会穿上一件很酷的T恤
while you'll be wearing a T-shirt
and that'll be cooler...
天啊 我忘了还有这
Ah, I forgot about that.
上面写着"我爱龟速船长"
...it will say "I love James May" on it.
第二天早上 哈蒙德一点也不急于
The next morning,Hammond was in no hurry
离开酒店
to leave the hotel.
-哈蒙德 -干啥?
- Hammond.- What?
-出来啊哈蒙德 -不要
- Hammond, come out. - No.
内什么 我还在收拾行装
No, I'm a bit...I haven't... I'm just packing my bag.
-已经8点45了 -我还在收拾
- It's quarter to 9:00.
- Yeah, I'm just packing my bag.
我在收拾
I'm packing.
事实上 我身体不太舒服
Actually, no, I'm not very well.
外面没什么人啊
There's nobody here.
-我感觉很糟糕 -哈蒙德!
- I'm poorly.- Hammond!
好吧 我要出来了
Right. I'm coming out.
啧啧啧啧
Ooh.
哦 看啊
Now, look.
-这太糟糕了 -是啊
- This is bad. - Yes.
不过我认为接下来的消息是更糟糕的
But I'm afraid the news gets even worse.
不会更糟了吧
It can't be any worse.
我们被选择了同样的车
We've both chosen the same car.
但是并不糟糕啊 不是么?
Well, that's not so bad, is it?
-你说只有一台车? -是啊
- You mean there's only one?- Yes.
所以 圣特罗佩街头
So, Saint-Tropez,
二男 一敞篷宾利
convertible Bentley, two men.
哦 我们看上去有点
Oh, we are looking...
我才意识到
Just realised.
两个男人坐在一台宾利里面
Two men in a Bentley.
并不只是宾利让我们很显眼
It isn't just the Bentley,
we ought to make that plain.
而是敞篷的问题
It's any convertible.
任何两个男人坐进一部敞篷车
Put two men in a convertible car,
打开车顶之后 问题立刻就出现了
take the roof off and instantly, questions are raised.
好吧 至少在车里 别人看不见我的T恤
Still, at least in the car, they couldn't see my T-shirt.
直到
Until...
我为什么在这停车?
Why are you pulling over here?
我想看点东西
I just want to have a look at something.
-看啥? -就是一些东西嘛
-What? -Just stuff.
-什么东西 -呃 我想看看那些船
- What stuff? -Just... I want to look at the boats.
你到底要干什么
What are you doing?
-这地方不错啊 -我不想停下来
- It's a nice place.
- I don't want to stop.
-这么多人... -出来啊
- There's people......- Just get out.
-不要 -要
-No. -Yes.
-不要! -要!
-No! -Yes.
不要 我要躲起来
No, I'm going to hide.
我不要出去 我就钻进去
I'm not getting out.
I'm getting in here.
就剩下我自己了
I'm on my own.
额滴神啊
Oh, God.
我打算走远点丢下他
I'm just going to go for a walk and leave him.
快结束这一切吧
Make this end.
我就是打赌输了嘛
I Lost a bet.
天啊
Oh, God.
大猩猩我们可以走了么?
Jeremy, can we go now?
不行
No.
这些游艇哪个有螺旋桨
Do any of these boats have propellers
还有哪个现在就可以启动离开的?
and are any of them likely
to be running right now?
又是拍照的 这里八卦围观群众还真多
Paparazzi again.There's quite a lot of paps here.
是啊 我们赶紧走吧
Yeah. So let's go.
但是出现了一个小问题
There was, however,a small problem.
-是在这里么
-本来就是在这个地方吧
-Was it... -Is this where it was?
-是啊 -显然现在不在了
- Yes. - Well, it's not, is it?
我来告诉你原因吧
I tell you why it's not.
这里是不能停车的
You can't park here, can you?
你能在这里停车么? 被允许的么...什么?
Can you park here?Are you allowed to... What?
你不能在这停啊 旁边画了一个车被拖走的图
No, you can't park here or that's a picture of a car being towed.
-你知道 我真的是 -车被拖走了?
- Do you know, I genuinely...
- Has the car been towed away?
是的
Well, yes.
你在这等我
Just you wait here
我去取车
and I'll go get it.
-放松点 -好吧
- Just relax. - Yeah.
并没有多远啊 我会在一个小时之内回来
It's not far, actually, I'll be back in an hour.
我相信此时此刻应该会有一个人比我更悲催
I'm sure somebody somewhere at some time has been unhappier.
两小时后
求你了 求你了 求你了 求你了
Please, please, please, please.
这一点也没意思 一点也没意思
No, not funny. Not even halfway funny.
杰瑞米把这该死的车门打开
Open the damn door.
Jeremy, open the door.
你怎么做到的?
How do you do that?
我进来了
I'm getting in.
现在你也许会疑惑
Now, at this point you may be wondering
为什么我们两人都选择了宾利
why both of us chose a Bentley.
一部分原因是我们认为现在的宾利很漂亮
Well, partly it's because we think that these days, it looks good.
最重要的是 现在还装备了一台
But mostly it's because it's now available
更轻量化 而且声浪更棒的4升V8发动机
with a brilliant lighter, louder 4-litre V8.
但哈蒙德脑中最惦记的却不是这个
Not that this was foremost in Hammond's mind.
-杰瑞米克拉克森 -到
- Jeremy Clarkson. - Yes.
你是不是把我的座椅加热开到最大了?
Have you put my seat heater on full?
是啊
Yes, I have.
哦 老兄这实在是
Oh, mate, that's...
-哦耶! 整到你了 -哦!
- Yes! Result. - Oh!
太糟糕了
Just horrific.
-这就是我想要的结果 -哦!
- That's a result right there. - Oh!
然后我得到了另外一个期待的结果
Then I got another result.
一条干净的 开放公路
A clear, open road.
可能会有一点颠
"It's got a bit of poke."
-哦哦 -这就是本来就该有的声音
- Whoa! - Oh, that's how it should sound.
你知道这是怎样的感觉么?
Do you know what it feels like?
-一台跑车应有的感觉 -是啊
- An sportscar. - It does.
你把我的座椅加热打开了么?
Have you put my seat heater on?
是啊
Yes, I have.
我实在是对不...
I'm really sor...
绝对是一台很棒的车
It's a machine, this.
你好 靓车!
Hello, machine!
这款车让我喜欢的一个主要原因就是
One of the reasons why I like this car so much,
与宾利的徽章无关
you know it isn't just a Bentley badge,
这款车克服了众多的工程难题
there's some properly difficult
engineering that's gone into this car.
杰瑞米 你是不是又把我的座椅加热打开了
Jeremy, have you put my seat heater on again? You...
这一点也不
That's not... I...
哦
Oh.
如果我坐的高一点
别人就能把我的T恤看的更清楚
And if I lift myself up,they can see my T-shirt better
如果我坐下去就被烤焦了  上帝啊!
and if I sit down, I cook. God!
聪明的引擎
So, clever engine,
智能的四驱系统
clever four-wheel-drive system,
最近越来越漂亮的外观
looks a lot better these days.
美妙的声浪
Great noise.
一台伟大的车子
It's a great car.
问题是 这车仍然有鲁尼的味道
The problem it has still is that Rooney flavour.
我说鲁尼的味道是指
The whiff of Wayne means
开着它出现 你会感觉不好意思
you do feel embarrassed to turn up in it.
哈蒙德!
Hammond!
不要再打开我的座椅加热了
Stop putting my seat heater on.
尽管座椅和车辆与日头一样热辣
Soon, despite the hot seats,
the hot car and the hot sun,
但是气氛开始变得冷凝了
the atmosphere became frosty.
因此我们决定分开
So we decided to split up.
我决定去看一座现在已经大部分坍塌的建筑
And then I decided to look at a building that had mostly fallen over.
看啊
Look at this.
这里面有头野猪 看啊
Yes, look, there's a wild boar,there we are.
这是一幅狩猎图
This is a hunting scene.
哈蒙德 这有一幅狩猎图!
Hammond, there's a hunting scene!
哈蒙德!
Hammond!
这应该是一座陵寝
It's like there's a mausoleum
-有类似于凯旋门的拱门
-别跟我说话 我不在乎
- and a sort of triumphal arch.
- Don't talk to me, I don't care.
我不想听 我也不想知道 我真的不想!
I don't want to hear about it.
I don't want to know, I really don't!
我受够了
I'm sick of it.
太荒唐了 我吃了螃蟹的眼睛
This is ridiculous. I've eaten crab's eyes,
我看了一座来自于故事当中的阳台
说真的 现在开始 我要做主了
I've looked at a balcony from a story.
No, seriously, it's my turn.
轮到我决定下一步要做什么了
It's my turn to decide what we do next.
我们接下来要做的就是去跑拉力赛
And what we're doing next is going rally driving.
-什么 开总裁去跑拉力? -不是
- What, in a Maserati Quattroporte?- No.
-那就是用幻影? -也不是
- And a Rolls-Royce Phantom?- No.
我有个好主意
I've had a good idea.
这里是桑布尔赛道
This is the circuit Sambre,
充满了法国拉力赛的残酷考验
endless kilometres of unrelenting French rally stage.
试替哥对这里了如指掌
And a place The Stig knows well.
-要怎样 -这个嘛
- What? - Well,
这就是试替哥的避暑山庄啊
this is The Stig's summer retreat, yeah?
每年夏天他都来这边 干这个
He comes here every year and does that.
-而且他说... -你说干这个是什么意思
- And he says... - What do you mean, he does that?
在冬天 他去开雪地赛道
夏天一到 他就来这儿
Well, in winter he goes ice racing.
Summer, he comes here.
三个礼拜 不停的干这个
Three weeks of that he does.
-什么 都不带休息? -对 钻进汽车 三个礼拜
- What, non-stop? -Yeah, gets in the car, three weeks,
三礼拜后 钻出汽车 回家
and then three weeks later,
gets out, goes home.
这就是他的假日
不管怎样 他说我们可以用这个赛道
That's his holiday. Anyway, he says we could use it
来开拉力
to do our rally driving.
-天太热了 -啊哈
- It's too hot. - Dah!
我正好也想到这个问题了
I have actually thought of that.
-你喜欢敞篷车不是么 -没错
- You like a convertible, don't you? - Yeah.
那我们干嘛不用敞篷车来开拉力呢
Why don't we rally-drive convertibles?
-灰尘太多 -拜托 就帮我这一次忙
- It's too dusty. - Now, do one thing for me,
我们出去弄两辆敞篷车
we're going to go and get
some convertibles,
把他们改装成拉力车 然后干这个!
turn them into rally cars and do that!
我不会开拉力赛啊
I can't do rally driving.
-很简单啊 你只要... -我干不来啊!
- It's easy, just... - I can't!
我在没抓地力的路面上不会...
I can't drive on loose surfaces...
过了很久
这是我的选择
This is what I've got.
尼桑 350Z
Nissan 350Z.
3.5升V6
Three-and-a-half-litre V6,
276匹马力 后轮驱动
276 brake horsepower, rear-wheel drive.
你可能看着它 心想
Now, you might be looking
at it, thinking, "Well,
它看上去不太像拉力车啊
"it doesn't look much like a rally car."
但别急 这车可是Datsun 240Z的
But hold on,this car is a direct descendant
直系后代
of the Datsun 240Z,
那可是曾经统治过国际拉力赛场的赛车
a car that owned world rallying.
所以这车可谓血统纯正
So this has got history.
它必定会表现得很棒
It's going to be brilliant.
我选了一辆宝马
I've got a BMW.
完全没有半点拉力血统
这也是我喜欢它的原因
No history of rallying at all,
it's one of the reasons I like it.
别这样 给我们说说它多大排量
Well, come on, tell us about it,
what engine has it got?
2.5升直6
Two-and-a-half-litre straight 6.
比尼桑少了一升 马力呢?
1000cc less than the Nissan. Power?
192?
大概少了80 扭矩呢？
That's about 80 horsepower less. Torque?
180.
-大概也少了80 -很好!
- That's about 80 torques less. - Good!
-很好是什么意思 -就是很好
-What do you mean, "good"? -Good!
杰瑞米 你在这事上还没进入竞争状态啊
Jeremy, you're not really getting into the competitive spirit of this.
我不喜欢在没有摩擦力的地方开车
I don't like driving without friction!
敞篷拉力赛会马上成为下一个热点
Open-top rally is going to be the next big thing.
我们赶紧把这些车改装成拉力车去
Let's go and convert these into rally cars.
这意味着我们要找到个车间 然后放音乐
This meant finding a workshop and cueing the music.
搞定
Got it.
唔 赞
Oh, yes.
天啊 我真厉害
God, I'm good.
这就应该能把我和理查德在马力上
That will make up for the horsepower deficit
的差距补回来了
that I have on Richard's car.
手写"涡轮"
TURBO
八月先生
This is August.
四月先生
Now Mr April.
我的防滚架搞定了
My roll-cage is complete.
第二天 我们的战车蓄势待发
The next day,
our cars were ready.
天气也一样
- And so was the sky.
这真是太棒了
This is all just fantastic.
突然间 就变成了完美的拉力天气
Suddenly, perfect rallying
weather is coming.
一点小雨 泥泞 山上还有点雾气
Bit of rain, mud, mist on the hills,
我的车也状态完美
and my car is now perfect.
我并没有改得过头
Haven't gone over the top
with the modifications.
新轮毂 新轮胎 防滚架
New wheels, new tyres, roll-cage,
赞助商贴纸 BBC要求不能用真的
sponsorship stickers,
can't have real ones,
但我们伪造了赞助商 让你感受赛车的氛围
BBC objects, but we've made 'em up
to put you in the mood.
车内 赛车座椅 四点式安全带 足够了
Inside, racing seat,
full harness, that's enough.
这应该是完美的一天
This is going to be amazing.
我就照他抄了
I just copied him.
而现在他就要在泥地里开他的达特桑了
And now he's going to drive about
in his Datsun in the mud.
他说的没错 我等不及了
He was right I couldn't wait.
啊 爽
Oh, yes!
天上下雨 我在跑拉力赛 真是完美啊
It's actually raining, I'm in a rally.
This is perfect!
在吃了一路这么多傻缺食物 看了那么多石头后
After all the stupid food
and looking at rocks.
能够在这里干这样一件由衷让人激动
而且如此真实的事情
to come out and do something
genuinely exciting and real and...
我觉得我复活了
I've come alive.
嗷 爽
Oh, yes!
理查德 现在 还在外面
Hammond is out now in that.
那个人已经疯了!
The man is insane!
来吧 让我再爽爽 来啊
Bring it on, let's have more. Come on!
这还叫下雨?
You call that rain?
喔吼吼吼
Oh!
这是当下全世界我最喜欢的地方
This is my favourite place
in the world now.
啊
Ah!
不好意思 理查德 给我解释一下
I'm sorry, Hammond,
do try to explain it to me,
我怎么也弄不明白
'cause I'm struggling to get it.
这是好一阵子以来 我最欢乐的时光
It's about the most fun
I've had in a very long time.
我理解为什么试替哥会来这儿了
I can see why The Stig comes here.
-你浑身都是泥啊 -没错
- You're covered in mud.
- Yeah.
-天上还打着响雷啊 -没错我知道
- There's a massive thunderstorm raging.
- Yeah, I know.
我知道 就连天气也比前几天要好 完美极了
I know, even the weather's better here.
It's perfect.
你说比前几天要好是什么意思
What do you mean, it's better?
-理查德 我真必须要这么干么 -没错
- Hammond, do I have to do this?
- Yep.
今天听我的 这就是我们今天要做的事情
It's my thing today,
and this is what we're doing.
所以 为了表明我多么的有肚量
And so, to show
what a good sport I am,
我满足他
I obliged.
哦老天爷
Oh, God's truth!
哦疼疼疼
Oh! That hurt.
恩 不舒服
So, discomfort...
嗷这简直太让人不爽了
Oh! That's just horrible!
危险
Danger.
凄惨 冷
Misery, cold.
以30km/h的时速滑行
Slithering around at 21 miles an hour.
哦哦去他娘的...
Oh, no! Bloody...
我被淋了一身屎黄浆水
I've just had a brown shower.
这真的是最后一根稻草
That really was the final straw.
然后我发现这居然不是
And then it turned out it wasn't.
好了 我们跑过了 熟悉了这个赛道
So, we got the hang of it,
we now know the course, yeah?
下面是计时赛
Time for timed laps.
-什么 -那 接下来开始计时
- What?
- Well, we do timed laps now,
我们这样来 如果我们各开十圈
that's what we do.
I reckon if we do 10 each
就能看出我们的稳定性如何
and then we can just work out
how consistent we are,
究竟在哪里能快上个几秒 没错吧
where we can just
shave those extra seconds out, yeah?
明天 你要被我逼着吃
Tomorrow, you are going to eat
獾的左蛋蛋
a badger's left teste.
所以 无视常识的我们
And so, flying
in the face of common sense,
又回到了赛道上
we got back out there.
计时赛 所以真的是非常关键
Timed laps now, so it's really critical
你需要足够勇敢 持续踩下油门
to just be brave enough
to keep that power in.
计时赛 那有什么意义啊
What's the point
of timed laps?
他比我多了80 嗷... 多了80bhp
He's got 80 more horsepower...
Oh! ...more than I have.
他开拉力比我厉害
He's better at it than I am.
他还有一套限滑差速器
And he's got
a limited-slip differential.
我没有那东西
I haven't got one of those.
因此 在过弯的时候 根本控制不了
一个轮子在不停空转
So, when I go round the corner,
one wheel spins and that's It.
喔吼吼吼 操控正确的时候感觉真是太爽了
Woo-hoo! God, it feels
good when you get it right.
哇!
Whoa!
嗷 嗷 天啊
Oh! Oh, my!
他会被...哈哈哈哈
He will have been...
哦他开过来了 我从这就能看到他的牙齿
Oh, here he comes,
I can see his teeth from here.
好了 在拉力赛道上超车 这可不多见
Right, overtaking on a rally stage.
This is interesting.
哦他要超过去了
Oh, he's coming through!
哦不 那个小不点伯明翰人超过去了
Oh, no! The hideous little Brummie
has torn past!
啊哈 套你一圈
A-ha! Got you!
哦他过去了 他把各种情况...
Oh, he's done it......
Oh, he's just made everything
变得更糟了 我啥都看不见了
much worse now, I can't see a thing.
眼镜上全是泥
Muddy goggles.
我想弄断他胯下的所有骨头
Every bone in his crotch,
that is what I'm going to break.
嗷 呸
Oh!
没过多久 天气变得更坏了
Soon, the weather got so bad,
连理查德也看不清赛道了
even Hammond couldn't
see where he was going.
操 操 嗷
Shit! Shit! Oh!
所以 他建议我们休息 来一顿特制的拉力午餐
So, he suggested we stop
for one of his special rallying lunches.
恩 赞 大吃一顿
Mmm. Okay, tuck in.
-真的? -嗯嗯
- Really?
- Mmm-hmm.
吃这个是因为当地以热狗出名的么
'Cause this part of France
is famous for its hotdogs.
它上面可是有法国芥末
It's got French mustard on it.
-是啊 -等一下
- Yeah...
- Wait a minute.
怎么
What?
你知道这个香肠里有什么吧
You do know what's
in that sausage, don't you?
-香肠啊 -猪的指甲
- Sausage.
- Pigs' toenails,
眼睫毛
eyelashes...
闭嘴给我好好享受 不管怎样
在你享受的时候 我拿到了我们的圈速
Shut up and enjoy it. And, anyway, while
you enjoy it, I've got the timings here.
我大约在1分16 1分13这个水平
I'm around the 1:16, 1:13,
that kind of mark.
-嗯哼 -你在1分53 1分46
- Mmm-hmm.
- You're 1:53, 1:46...
我耳朵里都进泥了
I've got soil in my ears!
1分35 1分40 所以基本上很明确
135, 140... Basically, what this
is showing is that I am clearly
我比你强太多了
a lot better at this than you.
-我和你做个交易 -什么
-I'll do you a deal.
-What?
我们再开一圈
We will do one more lap.
决一死战的一圈
Do-or-die lap.
如果我开得比你快的话 我们立刻走人
If I'm faster, we leave immediately.
-如果你比我快 -对
-If you're faster than me?
-Yes.
好 如果我比你快 我们一直开到天黑
All right, well, if I'm faster,
we carry on till dark.
-你觉得怎样 -嗯嗯
- You'll do that?
- Mmm-hmm.
-真的? -嗯嗯
- Seriously?
- Mmm-hmm.
好啊
All right.
我先出发
I went first.
法语 3 2 1 出发
出发了
And we're off.
其实我不光想要赢他 我还想羞辱他
Right, now, I don't want to just
beat him, I want to humiliate him.
哦耶 就应该这样
Oh, yes! That was correct.
喔!
Oh!
刚才下面有一个巨大的坑啊
That was a monstrous dump
from below there.
大自然也加入了我们
Nature is joining in with us now.
这真是欢乐无比啊
Oh, this is just epically good fun.
好了杰里米 我觉得你要是只比我慢1分以内
All right, Jeremy, I reckon if you get
within a minute of that,
我会很惊讶的 你没机会了
I'll be staggered. Not a chance.
我自信满满
Filled with determination,
策"马"阵前 准备出击
I lined up the BMW on the start line.
3 2 1 出发
恩 我绝对会赢
Right, I am going to win this
然后我们就不用再干这个了
and then we can stop doing it.
这会是...噢慢着
That's... Oh! Hang on a minute.
耶
Yes!
你觉得怎么样
What do you think of that?
悄悄的干活 打枪的不要
Sneaky beaky. Yes!
耶!
Yes!
连老天爷都站在我这边
The gods are on my side.
这回的圈速绝对慢不了
This is going to be one hell of a Lap!
随后我们一起去看我们跑的怎么样
We then met up to see how we'd done.
哈蒙德 你的成绩是1分17秒3
Richard Hammond, you did
it in one minute, 17.3.
虽然比不上我的最快圈速 但也不算慢
已经是个很高的起点了
- Not my fastest but not bad.
- Well, it was a standing start.
-那是 绝对的 -继续 然后呢
It was, yes, of course it was.
Yes, go on, them.
-我是 28秒 -多少
- Me, 28 seconds...
- Yes?
一分多少
One minute what?
没有一分 就是28秒
28 seconds.
你怎么可能连一分钟都不到
How did you find a minute in the...
-不可能吧 -只能说我是终极驾驶机器
- I mean...
- Ultimate driving machine.
还有宝马Z4的功劳
And a BMW Z4.
是吗
Really?
我立马开溜
I left immediately.
然后踏上了前往波城的最后350英里
And set off on the 350-mile drive to Pau
驾驶着一辆V12阿斯顿马丁
in a V12 Aston Martin.
而哈蒙德开着一辆大众甲壳虫
Hammond, meanwhile,
was in a Volkswagen Beetle
和往常一样抱怨着
and moaning, as usual.
他这个作弊已经无法无天了
His cheating is getting out of control.
这样的话还有什么意思
要是他动不动就用Stig做替身
There's no point doing anything
if he's just going to borrow The Stig
或者抄近路 这是我能想到的唯一可能性
or cut a corner, which I can only
imagine is what he did in that instance.
他肯定抄了一条相当近的路 这也太明显了吧
It must have been one hell
of a corner, he can't even cheat well!
我承认我那近路抄的有点夸张
I admit my shortcut was a bit short.
而且耗时有点短得离谱 不过看看好的一面
And the time was a bit implausible.
But look,
不仅天气好多了
我现在还开上了阿斯顿马丁Vanquish
the weather is improving and now
I'm in an Aston Martin Vanquish.
这车真心了不起
This is a truly magnificent car.
算是这么长时间以来最好的一辆马丁
Best Aston yet by a long way.
它是介于狂野的DBS和温和的Virage
It's a blend of the hardcore DBS
之间的一种调和
and the slightly softer Virage.
简直是太完美了
It's just tremendous.
下面我就要请出哈蒙德
And now I shall hand you
over to Richard Hammond,
来向你解释为什么他那辆保时捷911
who shall try to explain
why the Porsche 911
在某些鬼知道的方面
that he's driving
is in some way different
跟所有老款的911有什么不同
to all the Porsche 911s
that have gone before.
他居然还有脸说911都长一个样
How can he go on about 911s
all being the same?
那咱们来看看所谓的阿斯顿马丁 系列
Let me talk you through
the Aston Martin range.
Vantage V8, V12 Vantage,
DB9  DBS  Virage 还有前面那货
DB9, DBS, Virage, that.
那才叫一个模子里刻出来的吧
they're all exactly the same.
阿斯顿马丁设计了这个造型
Aston Martin came up with the design.
他们觉得 哎 这看起来不错
thought, "Oh, that looks pretty.
不如给它起不同的名字吧
这样就会有更多的人来买了
"Let's call it lots of different things
and then more people will buy it."
眼前就是个例子
It's just another one.
同一辆车取名为C2 C2S C4 C4S
C2, C2S, C4, C4S,
还可以叫GT2 GT3 Turbo 997 996 993
GT2, GT3, Turbo, 997, 996, 993...
新911的型号叫991
The new 911 is called the 991,
车身比上一代要更宽更长
it's longer and wider
than the previous 911.
新引擎 新变速箱 新内饰和新的转向系统
It's got a new engine, new gear box,
new interior and new steering.
这是最关键的地方 911第一次
This is the critical point,
for the first time,
使用了电子转向而不是液压转向
the steering is electric
rather than purely hydraulic.
就当我刚刚找着状态的时候
Just as I was getting into the groove,
杰里米又找了个地方停下了
Jeremy pulled off again.
你又干嘛啊
What now?
既然我们明天就要到波城了
Well, I thought it would be a good idea,
since we're at Pau tomorrow,
我觉得我们应该重新熟悉一下
to reacquaint ourselves with the concept
在摩擦力作用下驾驶的概念
of driving while under
the influence of friction.
我不喜欢摩擦力
I don't like friction.
波城啊哥们 那可是波城
Pau, mate. It's Pau.
人家从1901年就开始赛车了
They've been racing there since 1901.
Fangio曾经在那里比过赛
Fangio has raced there,
还有Jim Clark Jackie Stewart
那可不是一个随便的地方
Jim Clark, Jackie Stewart.
This is a big deal.
那可是 好比所有汽车爱好者的伯利恒圣城
This is... It's Bethlehem
for any motoring enthusiast.
可那跟这个赛道有什么关系
So, what's it got to do with that?
我们得找到比赛的状态才行
We've got to get match fit.
这样等我们明天到了波城
And then when we get to Pau tomorrow...
-我们就能值回票钱 -没错
- We'll be worthy of it.
- Mmm-hmm.
一上赛道 我顿时就开心了起来
Straightaway,I was very happy.
没有湿乎乎的赛道 没有泥巴
No wet track, no mud,
没有下不停的雨 也没有得白喉的可能
no rain, no diphtheria.
这真是一条紧凑蜿蜒的赛道
This is one
tight and twisty little track.
好的 下面我们就让这辆阿斯顿
Right, now, let's turn the Aston
从公路车变的更赛道化一点
from a road car into something
more track-based.
按下这个让悬挂变得更硬的按钮
We'll push this button here,
that firms up the suspension.
再按这个S按钮 我猜它的意思是 傻缺模式
and then push this one, S,
I think it stands for "silly".
因为当你按下它的时候 准备好了吗
'Cause when you push it... Ready?
整辆车好似瞬间变身 "嗯 要干嘛？"
好比向狗狗下达"朝前走" 的命令一样
The whole car goes, "Hmm, what?"
It's like saying "walkies" to a dog.
"真的 主人？ 向前走？"
"Oh, really? WaIkies?"
这辆车所用的引擎跟老版Vanquish一样
This has the same basic engine that
was fitted to the original Vanquish.
这在当时是能够比肩法拉利550的引擎
And that was comparable
at the time to the Ferrari 550
或者是575
or 575.
但从那以后 法拉利继续发展
人家都生产出F12那样的车了
Since then, Ferrari have moved on,
they're at the F12 now.
这车的变速器甚至都不是双离合
This doesn't even have
a double-clutch gearbox.
而是老式的七速顺序变速器
It's an old 7-speed slushmatic.
每次换挡都像是一个年长的男仆完成的
Each gear is delivered
by an elderly butler.
-我想换三档了 吉夫斯 -没问题先生
"I'd like third now, Jeeves."
"Certainly, sir, I'll just
我就去拿 应该放在餐具室了
"pop off and get it.
I think it's in my pantry.
给您拿来了 先生
"There you are, sir."
换挡非常顺畅 应付公路绰绰有余
但在赛道上就不合适了
Very smooth,
lovely on the road, not brilliant here.
这车开起来有点像方舟
It's a bit of an ark, this.
而且是非常 非常漂亮的方舟
It's a very pretty ark.
不过每当在赛道上攻入一个弯的时候
But when you stick it into
a corner on a track...
你能够感觉到在这副碳纤维的身躯下
you know that beneath
the carbon fibre body,
每个零件都感觉有点年事已高
everything's a bit old.
不过如你所见 倒不是说老就一定不好
Not that theres much
wrong with old, as you can see.
与此同时 在落后我很多的地方
Mean while, far behind...
哈蒙德在新911强大的抓地力下撒着欢儿
Hammond was
revelling in the new 917's grip.
天呐 这玩意就和长在地上似的
God, this thing is planted.
依旧是3.8升的水平对置六缸引擎
Still a 3.8-litre flat six,
依旧位居车尾 依然那么紧凑
it's still mounted at the back
of the car, it's still compact.
不过最大的问题 还是电子转向
The big issue, though,
is that electric steering.
它根本没有向我沟通 没有
它本应该反馈给我各种信息
It's not talking to me. It's not...
It should be telling me everything
比如加速过弯的时候前面切弯稍浅
by going slightly
light at the front under power.
这意味着前轮比于普通的车
It means the front wheels can move
around a little bit more
可以再多打一点方向
than they would in an ordinary car.
而方向盘本应该告诉我这一切
And the steering wheel
should be telling me about that,
这才能让我知道它是911
that's what lets me know it is a 911
而不是R8或者捷豹什么的
and not an R8 or a Jaguar.
你要问我这车有没有那种911韵味
Does it feel like a 911?
我还真不觉得有
I don't think it does.
要是为波城选战车的话
我想要比它跟纯一点的
And for Pau, I want something
that's more of a 911.
而我已经有了个很好的想法
And I've had a very good idea for that.
我应该用这车
I shall be using this,
全新的保时捷911GT3
the brand-new Porsche 991 GT3.
我太想开这车了
I am desperate to drive it.
更轻 更强 更快
It's lighter, lower, faster.
它就是我的独角兽
This is my unicorn,
我的女神
my Helena.
GT3或许在赛道方面更专业
Track-focused the GT3 may be,
但是在波城 它跟我的选择根本没得比
but at Pau, it would be no
match for my choice.
单座的BAC Mono
The single-seater BACMono.
我们测试赛道上有史以来最快的车之一
One of the fastest cars ever
to take on the Top Gear test track.
极致的简洁 轻盈 灵动 平衡
Purity simplified,
light, agile, balanced.
完美
Perfect.
当工作人员正为明天的大日子准备车子时
As men set about fettling our cars
for the big day...
我们俩回顾了在这段旅程中我们所驾驶的
we ruminated on all the boats
and bikes and cars
所有摩托车 汽车 船
that we 'd used on our journey.
哈蒙德!
- Hammond!
试图找出我们最喜欢的那一个
And we tried to work out
which one we 'd liked the best.
我大爱那辆小嘉年华ST 真心的
I loved that little Fiesta ST,
I really did.
虽然听着很疯狂 但那辆福特T型我也喜欢
I actually loved driving the Model-T,
crazy though that is.
杜卡迪也令人十分享受
I enjoyed the Ducati.
但是不知为何 法拉利F12确实让我倾心
But for some reason, the Ferrari F12
has really stayed with me.
我觉得它有那种韵味和戏剧性
更不用说它的速度!
I thought it had presence and drama
and it's fast!
我不会选SLS 因为日常开着有点过了
I wouldn't have the SLS 'cause
that's too much to use every day.
高尔夫GTI会有点不够用
Golf GTI isn't quite enough.
布加迪威龙的话就完全不是一个级别了
Bugatti Veyron, I mean it's
the other end of the scale, then.
也太过了 宾利的话
Too much. Bentley...
虽然是辆好车但是...
我知道究竟喜欢哪个了
Oh, it's a great car but...
I've worked out what I'd have.
Riva Aquarama那条船
The Riva Aquarama.
-那是你最喜欢的 车 -是的
- That's your favourite car?
- Yes.
要是让我天天用 我会选那个
不过那样我就得搬家喽
That's what I'd use every day.
I'd have to move house.
选出我们最喜欢的那辆
我们重新坐上了自己的公路车
With that decided,
we climbed back into our road cars
驶上前往波城的最后一段路
for the final push to Pau.
即将到达波城 我俩十分激动
We were very excited by what lay ahead,
太激动了 以至于我们把摄制组落了很远
so excited that we left
the camera crew far behind.
当他们终于追上的时候 却出了点小状况
And when they finally caught up with us,
there was a bit of a problem.
护照是吧
You mean, passports?
对 坏了
Oh, right
法国的警察和女警们
The French policemen and lady policemen
坚持要我们交出所有的钱
insisted that we should give
them all our money.
而在一段长谈之后
And then after quite a long chat,
他们不允许我们在法国境内再开车了
they decided it would be best
if we didn't drive in France any more.
好 没问题
Yeah, okay.
那么伴随着这个爆炸性新闻 我们该结束了
And on that bombshell,
it is time to end.
非常感谢各位的收看 再见
Thank you very much for watching,
goodbye.
你个纯种的笨蛋
You total plonker!
我可不想坐进一辆标志 或者波罗
I don't want to go in a Peugeot or a Polo
或者是沃克斯豪尔 Zafira
Or this Vauxhall Zafira.
我们要搭顺风车啊 怎么还能那么挑剔
Can you be picky
when you're a hitchhiker?
我觉得完全可以啊 反正有那么多选择
I should think so.
There's plenty of choice.
老子也不想坐雪铁龙
Don't want to go in that Citroen.
不要着急关呦